實習醫生格蕾
—
第十季  第六集  "讀懂一個人"
"Map of You"
■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
翻譯：喵記 小蠻腰 四方蝦 J小米 SMU囧 想往D 宅女之后 小shy
■
校對：喵記   月月   AS    總監：月月
時間軸：NO.Zero    兜兜兜爹    后期：Ghost
■
研究人員目前正在
Researchers are currently working
繪制人類大腦架構圖
to make a map of the human brain.
這興許是有史以來最復雜的
It may be the most complex map
架構
ever created...
-早安  -早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
上十億的神經發生萬億次的神經傳遞
Billions of neurons making trillions of connections.
而最初  它們看似完全無章可循
At first glance, they seem completely random.
小心燙
Careful. Hot.
然而  它們并非沒有規律
But there is nothing random about them.
這些神經傳遞都是有章可循
All these connections have to happen
并共有一套機制
in a specific pattern.
每種存在都有自己的功能
It is designed for a function.
這些傳遞決定了我們的一切  包括
These connections determine everything about us,
我們所愛的
what we love...
深惡痛絕的
what we hate...
我們的言語
what we say...
我們的行為
what we do...
我們做的每一個動作
Every action we take.
把手張開  米基
Open your hand, okay, Mickey?
這樣么
Like this?
正是  就這樣
Exactly. Like that.
叼爆了
Yeah, baby!
好的  現在合上
Okay, now close it.
不錯
Oh, yeah!
他想著各種動作時  我們看到大腦的
As he thinks about movements, we see brain activity
這  還有這  開始發亮
here and here. These areas lighting up.
這個腦機接口讓一切變為可能
Now the brain-computer interface is the key
即使是像米基這樣的四肢癱患者
to new possibilities, whether it be robotic prosthetics...
裝的機械假肢
for quadriplegics like Mickey...
還能讓我再次完爆俄羅斯方塊
Or letting me kick ass at "Tetris" again.
大家伙來看這個
Hey, check this out, you guys.
不費吹灰之力啊
Hang loose!
誒  托瑞斯醫生呢
Hey, where's Dr. Torres?
她怎么能錯過這個
How's she missing this?
歷史性的突破啊
This is the best that we've ever done.
肖恩  再給她發個短信
Shane, text her again, will you?
-有什么不對勁嗎  -顳葉沒有任何反應
- Is something wrong? - There's not a lot of temporal lobe activity.
這里沒有發亮
Nothing lights up here.
-是不是傳感器連接的問題  -但愿如此
- Is it a bad connection in the sensor? - I hope so.
如果不是傳感器  那就是他大腦有問題了
If not, it's a bad connection in his brain.
給米基做個磁共振
Schedule Mickey for an M.R.I.
這個我出門的時候帶錯了
I brought this from home accidentally.
麻煩你把它和我那些尿片放一起吧
Can you just put it in with my diaper bag and stuff?
然后  我等會去找托瑞斯
And, uh, I'll try and find Torres.
感覺如何  小二年
What's up, second year?
-更上一層樓了喲  -這都是發的么
- This is a step up, right? - Are these assigned?
對啊  我們衣服上都繡了名字
Yes. There's a lab coat with your name.
你到底在高興什么啊
What are you so happy about?
才不告訴你
Can't tell you.
你肯定想知道  但不可說
You wish I could, but I can't.
所以就不要問啦
So please don't ask.
-怎么連個門都沒了  -就是啊
- Why are there no doors on these? - I know, right?
姨媽棉條都沒地兒藏了
Like, "Hello, tampons. Meet everyone."
海瑟·布魯克斯醫生
大伙兒  竟然有給海瑟·布魯克斯的白大褂
You guys, there's a coat here for Heather Brooks.
-天哪  -真的么
- Oh, my god. - Seriously?
他近來很怪啊
Okay, is he being weird?
沒過測試么
Did he fail the exam?
他直接離開了  都沒來一起慶祝
He left right after. He didn't come celebrate.
還有  他竟然親了我
Also, he kissed me.
說的跟真的似的  想得到挺美
Oh, yeah, he kissed her. It could be that.
完全能理解  我自己也有小秘密
I totally get it. I've got a secret thing going, too.
竟然沒咖啡  糟透了
There's no coffee here. This is bad.
只能告訴你某人親了我
I can't tell you who kissed me, though.
嗨
Hey.
嗨  我今早從你床上起來
Hey! I woke up at your place...
-發現又是我一人  -噢  我晚上在外頭
- alone, again. - Yeah, I was out late.
連著三晚都是這樣
This has been three nights now.
對  我每晚都出去了  沒別的原因
Yeah, I've been, uh, going out. That--that's all.
我的實習測試過了  你都沒打電話來問我
I passed my intern exam. I never heard from you.
是不是出什么事了
Is there something going on?
阿歷克斯  回答我
Alex, talk to me.
阿歷克斯
Alex?
終于走了  我還以為她不走了呢
Ugh. I thought she would never leave.
-怎么  -你收到我的短信了么
- Hmm? - So you got my texts?
我通過了測試
I passed my intern exam.
當然  我也回了啊
Yeah, yeah, I did. I-I replied.
回了  "恭喜"
I-I wrote "Congratulations."
我還想著能見見你呢
I hoped I would see you.
畢竟那晚我倆過得挺愉快嘛
I had such an amazing time the other night.
對  挺愉快的
Yeah, it was fun.
我覺得  我們可以更進一步
I feel like I'm ready to... take it further--
這個  也許不是個好主意
Um, you know, um, it's-- it's not a good idea,
是啊  上班不該談的
Um... at work?
完全理解
I totally get it.
-那今晚見  -噢
- See you tonight? - Mm-hmm.
你呼我
You paged me?
愛德華茲醫生  這是本·博斯克
Dr. Edwards, Ben Bosco,
-還有他妻子喬伊斯  -你好
- his wife Joyce. - Hi.
他踝關節骨折了
He's got an ankle fracture.
我們當時在機場的傳送走道上跑
That moving walkway thing at the airport--
因為要去趕阿拉斯加的飛機
We were running to catch our connection to Alaska--
去那看北極光嘛
Ahh, to see the northern lights.
結果他崴了一下
Then he steps off that thing,
然后我就聽到了
and I heard it. I heard it just go
-”?”的一聲  -就像劇烈的剎車聲
- crack. - Like the whole world slammed on the brakes,
-而我還在繼續跑  -于是就來這了
- and I kept going. - And here we are.
給他做個全身檢查  再喊骨科醫生來會診
He's gonna need a full workup and an ortho consult.
再做個胸腔照片  因為可能會要做手術
Also get a chest x-ray, 'cause it might be surgical.
記得告訴我結果
Keep me posted.
好了  我先去安排X光
Okay. I will get those x-rays.
-抱歉  -抱歉
- Oh! Excuse me. - Sorry. Oh! Sorry.
-你確定這沒關系  -我喊你來的  沒事
- You're sure it's not weird? - I called you.
羅賓斯還不知道我們在交往吧
Robbins doesn't know that we're dating, does she?
因為我可不想靠這個
'cause I just don't want to trade on our...
不管這是什么 換參觀手術的機會
Whatever this is to, uh, get to observe a surgery.
她不知道
No.
很好  我只是想專業點  你懂的
Good. I just like to keep it professional, you know?
-工作嘛  -當然
- At work. - Yeah, of course.
那個
Um, hey, uh...
真不能告訴別人么  因為我已經告訴幾個了
Are we not telling people? 'cause I told a couple people.
當然可以
Yeah, you could.
該告訴嘛
Uh, you should.
我也會告訴啦
I would.
那就好
Good. Good.
好了  既然是工作
Well, we are at work. So...
-多謝你請我來  -沒問題
- Thanks for the call. - Yeah.
-抱歉  -你好
- Oh. Excuse me. - Hi. Hello.
上班還帶女友來了
Bring your girlfriend to work day?
羅賓斯要給一個三月大的的畸胎瘤嬰兒做手術
Robbins has a teratoma in a 3-month,
而  艾瑪
And, uh, Emma--
瑪琳醫生
Doctor, uh, Marling--
想看看
is gonna observe.
真貼心啊
That's sweet.
這樣不會太奇怪吧  是嗎
This isn't gonna be weird, is it?
對我來說  不會
For me? Please.
對她來說會很奇怪嗎
Will it be weird for her?
我是說  她是那種會被前任嚇跑的人嗎
I mean is she-- is she the type to get freaked out by the ex?
該死
Damn it.
梅
Mer...
你在干什么
What's going on?
沒什么  我在
Oh, nothing. I'm--
我在決定選哪個研究項目
I'm just, uh, trying to decide on a research project.
有什么可選的
Decide between what?
沒什么  我能搞定
Nothing. I got it.
疼痛感不會消失的
This pain isn't going away.
我的左肩一直在疼
It's a constant pain in my left shoulder.
您覺得是什么原因引起的呢
And what do you think is causing that?
是不是摔著肩膀了
Were you injured in a fall?
你告訴我啊  你是我醫生
You tell me. You're my doctor.
對  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
只是你也是我的老師
It's just that you're also my teacher.
打擾一下  貝利醫生
Excuse me, Dr. Bailey...
你記不記得在哪讀到過一個未完成的
Do you remember reading somewhere
研究報告  是關于髂門靜脈移植的
about unfinished research on iliac-portal vein grafts?
-怎么了  -今天是上交
- Why? - Tonight is the deadline
國家衛生研究院研究基金申請的最后一天
to submit for the N.I.H. research grant I want.
我現在不確定
And I'm having trouble deciding
是選擇局部缺血...
between ischemia--
你要做出一番事業啊
Ah, you're peeing on a tree.
作為主治醫生的第一年都害怕搞砸
Yeah, first year attending scared of screwing up.
所以她選了那些簡單的病例
So, um, she takes the easy cases.
保持低調
She keeps a low profile.
但主治醫生的第二年就得有突出表現
But second year attending has got to step it up--
選一些典型病例  發表研究報告
take the flashy cases, publish the research,
確定研究領域  干出一番事業
mark her territory. Pee on some trees.
髂門靜脈  記不記得
Portal veins... any bells?
那是你母親的研究
It was your mother's.
"門靜脈插補術和髂靜脈移植"
"Portal vein interposition with iliac vein graft."
愛麗絲生病時正在研究這個
Ellis was working on it when she got sick.
在你給我的某本日記里有這個
It's in one of the journals you gave me.
該死
Oh, crap.
我有個同樣的杯子
I have a mug like that.
如果對于我的肩部疼痛
If you don't come back with a solid diagnosis
你無法給出明確的診斷
for my shoulder pain,
我就得要求你離開了
I'm gonna kick you off my case.
是作為老師還是病人
As my teacher or my patient?
出去
Get out.
我得給韋伯的肩部疼痛做出診斷
I need a differential diagnosis for Webber's shoulder pain.
關節炎  黏液囊炎
Arthritis, bursitis...
任何年齡大的人都有的"炎癥"
Any of the old people "-itises."
還在等我那個踝骨骨折病人的胸部CT
Still waiting on my broken ankle's chest scans.
你居然有咖啡
You got coffee.
阿歷克斯不跟我說話
So Alex isn't talking to me.
我猜是因為我逼著他
I think it's 'cause I pushed him to
和他游手好閑的老爸說話
talk to his deadbeat dad.
阿歷克斯有個老爸
Alex has a dad?
你跟肖恩談過了沒
Have you talked to Shane?
我還是希望這事能平息下去
I'm still hoping it'll go away.
肖恩親了我  我又沒親他
Shane kissed me. I didn't kiss him.
這是他的問題
It's his problem.
他的心臟上有個巨大的腫瘤
He has a huge tumor in his heart.
不
No...
他只是踝骨骨折了啊
He has a broken ankle.
好的  謝謝
Okay, yeah. Thank you.
-你沒事吧  -對啊  怎么了
- You okay? - Yeah, why?
我們今天早上測試了
Yeah, we tested the new sensors
米基·溫思勒的新傳感器
with Mickey Wenschler this morning.
結果非常成功
And--and it was a huge success.
但是他一直在問為什么你沒在那
But he kept asking why you weren't there.
你沒有...你沒有收到我的短信嗎
Uh, well, didn't you-- didn't you get my text?
你短信說  "我不去了"
Your text said, "Won't be there."
好吧  是這樣子的
Okay, well, uh, here's the thing--
搬回我家讓我覺得
Moving back into my place made me feel like
我真的需要搬回"我家"
I really need to move back into "My place,"
集中精力在成就我本人的事情上
You know, concentrate on what makes me, me.
我研究的是再生軟骨
I do regenerative cartilage.
這也是我的TED演講的主題
It's what my T.E.D. Talk was about--
你到底什么意思
What are you saying?
我不打算繼續那個項目了
I'm not going forward with the project.
而你應該繼續下去
You should totally run with it, though.
不  這是你的項目
No, this is your project.
米基是你的病人  我沒法做
Mickey's your patient. I can't do this.
我沒有時間  梅瑞迪斯和我
I don't have time. Meredith and I
得花大量時間照顧孩子們
are in over our heads with kids,
而且她也需要時間
and she needs time, too.
那我們放棄這個項目吧
So maybe we just drop it.
也沒什么壞處  對嗎
No harm done, right?
那你去跟米基·溫思勒說吧
Oh, and tell that to Mickey Wenschler.
米基會沒事的
Mickey will be all right.
愛德華茲  我剛才檢查了踝骨骨折
Edwards, I just saw your broken ankle.
不用手術  夾板固定就行
No surgery, just splint it.
他不會沒事的  那會殺了他的
He won't be all right. It's gonna kill him.
我知道
I know, right?
我做不到啊
I can't do this.
-這是你干的嗎  -我...
- Did you do this? - Uh, I...
我得去找凱普納
I need to find Kepner.
不行  這是誰打碎的
No, who broke this?
是我  抱歉  是我摔碎了
Yeah, sorry. I dropped it.
楊醫生  你能看一下這個嗎
Dr. Yang, uh, would you look at this?
-天哪  -這很糟糕  對嗎
- Holy--wow! - I mean, it's bad, right?
-你不能用這個的  -肖恩  等會說
- Look, this wasn't yours to use-- - Shane, not now!
左心室有一大片的動靜脈畸形瘤
This is a rat's nest of an A.V.M. in the left ventricle.
說不定已經擴展到心臟瓣膜了
It's probably pushing in on the valve.
如果不治療  他只能活幾個月
If it's not treated, he'll be dead in months.
他是因為踝骨骨折來的
He came in for a broken ankle.
現在我得去告訴他  他要死了
And now I have to tell them he's dying.
讓我看看血檢結果
Okay, let me look at the blood work,
然后我們一起告訴他們
and we'll tell them together.
天哪  太謝謝你了
God, thank you so much.
這地方像個迷宮
This place is a maze.
-那是羅賓斯醫生  -對
- That's Dr. Robbins? - Yeah.
那你是
And you are?
-羅賓斯醫生  我是艾瑪·瑪琳  -對
- Dr. Robbins, Emma Marling. - Oh, right.
-對  你是來觀摩手術的  -我希望
- Right, right, you're observing. - And I'm scrubbing in...
我能參加
I hope.
墨菲  抱歉  加上瑪琳醫生
Murphy, I'm sorry. With Dr. Marling,
我覺得手術臺都滿了  下次吧
I think the table's full. Um, next time?
我們剛給小艾琳的父母講解了手術
Okay, so we just gave little Erin's parents the pre-game,
然后我們就帶她去做手術
and we're about to take her up.
墨菲  你能帶她去找手術服嗎
Murphy, will you show her where to get some scrubs?
觀摩醫生
Visiting surgeon?
對  她是婦科和兒科醫生  正在研究
Yeah, maternal/fetal. She's researching
微創治療子宮畸胎瘤
minimally invasive in-utero teratomas.
她很性感  我只是說
And she's hot. I'm just saying
我會在一旁看著你的  以防你就范
It's good that I'll be there to chaperone.
怎么  不能拿這個開玩笑嗎
What, we're not joking about this yet?
手術室見了
See you in there.
給你
Here.
這是我母親的日記  你從哪找到的
This is my mother's journal. Where did you get this?
韋伯...讓我去他家了
Webber... made me go to his house.
我還要去搞清楚他的肩膀到底為什么疼
And I need to figure out why his shoulder hurts.
-我可以走了嗎  -可以
- Can I go? - Yeah.
-你們這是搞什么  -研究基金
- What was that about? - Research funding.
我正在糾結到底是局部缺血
I'm trying to decide between an ischemia study
還是我母親曾經做過的門靜脈研究
and this portal vein thing that my mother was working on.
做那個
Ooh! Do that.
可是這個都已經做好一半了
It's half-baked.
再加上我不喜歡沾我媽的光
A-and I don't like trading on my mother's name.
不  這完全是你的杰作
No, it's your story.
杰出的年輕外科醫生完成了
"Brilliant young surgeon finishes work
她去世母親未完成的工作
of dead brilliant mother surgeon"--
這太順理成章了  你要打響自己的名號
It writes itself. Invest in your brand.
你把我說的好像是個軟飲似的
You make me sound like a soft drink.
我也正是這么做的呀
That's what I'm doing.
重新對自己投資
Yeah, I'm reinvesting in myself.
-就沖著這個  -一起努力吧
- That's the perfect reason... - Right?
我也不干
not to.
肖恩  給你  好東西
Shane, here you go. Some good stuff in there.
-好好享受吧  -你不會明白的
- Enjoy. - Ugh. You don't get it.
這是米基的核磁共振結果
These are Mickey's M.R.I.s?
謝博德醫生  我想問您一下
Dr. Shepherd...I wondered if you'd mind
今天結束后  我跟別的醫生可以嗎
if I switch services after today.
-你是我點名要求的  -我知道
- I asked for you specifically. - I know.
我知道去年發生在你和布魯克斯之間的事
Look, what happened last year between you and Brooks,
也許是我當時有失公平
I think I may have been unfair,
而我也一直希望找個機會彌補
and I was hoping for a chance to make it right.
所以說  現在布魯克斯不在了
So...now that Brooks is gone...
-就由我頂替她  -該死的
- I get to take her place? - Oh, hell.
怪不得傳感器不發光呢
Well, that's why the sensors weren't lighting.
他長了個神經膠質瘤
He has a glioma.
你能治好他嗎
Can you treat it?
我可以用膠試試
I could try hitting it with some glue.
-膠  -栓塞膠  一般用在腦動靜脈畸形
- Glue? - Embolization glue. We use it for A.V.M.s.
我們把超能膠注射到血管中
We pump superglue into the vessels,
膠水凝固后便切斷了通往腫瘤的血液
the glue hardens, cuts off blood to the tumor.
我可以試試看
I could try it. Mm...
不行  血管直接連接到腦干
No. It goes all the way to the brain stem.
-太危險了  -那動手術呢
- It's too dangerous. - And going in surgically?
結果也是一樣
It's the same thing.
恐怕也是弊大于利
I'm afraid of doing more harm than good.
這是一個非常致命的腫塊
It's a very deadly mass.
是個巨大的靜脈畸形
It's a large veinous malformation...
如果不馬上加以治療
and without intervention immediately,
恐怕結果不堪設想
I'm afraid the prognosis is very bad.
沒錯  就是那個東西
Yeah, that's the thing.
我這幾年一直帶著它活的
Um, I have been dying of that for years.
你知道你心臟有腫瘤卻只字不提
You knew about this and you didn't mention it?
-抱歉  -在你的醫療記錄上沒有
- I'm sorry. - In your medical history, there's --
我滿腦子都是錯過航班的事
I was so hung up on missing our plane --
這是個不能動手術的動靜脈畸形瘤
It's an inoperable A.V.M.
他大概在一年
He was diagnosed with it, what, a y --
-一年半  -沒錯  前年就確診了
- Year and a half -- - Year before last, yeah.
-一月份  -而且是晚期
- January. - And terminal.
那我們還能怎么辦
So...what are you gonna do?
我們就辭了工作  把銀行里的錢都取了出來
So we just quit our jobs, cashed out all our accounts,
-然后開始旅游  -沒錯  開始干各種事
- and just started traveling. - Yeah, just doing stuff --
旅游  活動  基本上把剩余的一切時間
trips, activities, basically cramming as much living
都盡可能地填滿
as we could into the time we have left.
好吧  你的醫生  他  他
Okay, did your doctor -- did he or -- or --
或是她有沒有試過給你用輻射治療
or she, uh, try treating it with radiation?
-試過了  -靜脈卷呢
- Yeah, tried that. - Intravenous coiling?
也試過了  沒用
Mm-hmm. Yeah, no dice.
還有硬化劑
And the sclerosing agents --
那移植呢  或是
Uh, what about a transplant? Or what about...
還有很多
There are a lot of --
親愛的
Sweetie...
我知道這很難接受
I know it's hard.
對我們來說也是一樣
It was hard for us, too.
但是你必須學會放手
But you have to let it go.
因為我對此無能為力
Because there is nothing I can do about it.
很抱歉  最好的選擇就是
I'm sorry. The best course
不去管它  然后期待最好的結果
is to leave it alone and hope for the best.
但研究還是要繼續的  對吧
We'll keep doing the study, right?
-拜托  為什么不行  -因為太危險了
- Come on. Why? - Because it is too dangerous.
而且腫瘤可能會導致異常結果
Also the tumor could give us abnormal results.
那你要把腫瘤取出來呢
What if you take the tumor out?
-那我可以繼續做實驗了  -可以  但是
- I could keep doing the testing. - You could, but --
那就把它取出來呀
Then take it out, man!
我們離成功已經近在咫尺了
We're so close, right?
今天早上的結果跟上一次的相比
This morning, I was miles beyond anything
-簡直是天壤之別  -太危險了
- what I did last time -- - It's too dangerous.
我們得把你送進手術室  取出你的傳感器
We're gonna take you out there, remove your sensors,
然后還要縫合你的
and then we're gonna close
-開顱術  -要是我不簽同意書呢
- your craniotomy -- - What if I don't consent?
什么
What?
要是我說  除非你把我的腫瘤也取出來
What if I say you can't take your sensors back
不然就別想拿回你的傳感器呢
unless you take my tumor, too?
米基  我必須把傳感器取出來
Mickey, I need to take them out.
對不起  哥們
Sorry, bud.
拒絕訪問
Access denied.
除非把我的腫瘤摘除
You're not going in my head
不然你就別想碰我的腦子
unless you're leaving with that tumor.
能用上電熱封口器真是好呀
Lucky you use electro-thermal sealers.
我們做子宮內部手術時就用不了  太大了
They're too big to get in there when we do these in-utero.
忍耐我一下  艾瑪
Bear with me, Emma.
阿歷克斯  我需要你的建議
Alex, I need your advice.
如果你跟某人有了一夜情
What's your strategy when you have a one-night-stand --
都算不上是一夜情  就只是親熱了一下
not even -- you just make out with someone,
然后那個人就黏上來了  你怎么辦
and then they get way too attached?
你知道誰是這樣的人嗎
You know who's like that?
莉亞·墨菲
Leah Murphy.
真的嗎
Really?
是啊  我跟她也就上了一次要不就兩次床
Yeah, I slept with her one, maybe two times.
然后她就跟超能膠一樣粘著我
She stuck to me like glue.
那小妞從不認識你到跟你說"我愛你"
That girl goes from zero to "I love you"
只需要七秒
in seven seconds.
我從來從來都沒有過這種感覺
I've never, ever felt this way.
如果我告訴你們這個人是誰的話
And if I tell you guys who it is,
會給我  也會給這個人
it would cause so many problems for me
帶來太多問題  而且
and for this person, and...
說不準還會影響整間醫院
god, for the hospital, probably.
所以拜托你們別問
So please don't ask.
會不會是跟心臟相關呢
Could it be heart-related?
-他有心室衰竭  -什么
- He had ventricular failure. - What?
韋伯的肩膀疼
Webber's shoulder hurts.
你跟阿歷克斯聊過嗎
Hey, did you talk to Alex?
我試過  但是他只是不停地躲我
Yeah, I tried. He just keeps running away.
他這是要甩了你  他當初對我就是這樣的
He's dumping you. It's what he did with me.
他會假裝你不存在  直到你真的就不存在了
He'll pretend you're not there until you're not there.
等你不在了
And when you're not there,
他就會跟其他人上床
he'll have sex with someone else.
你干嗎粘我的杯子
Why are you gluing my mug?
這不是你的杯子  這是謝博德的
It's not yours. It's Shepherd's.
這個馬克杯該我負責
The mug was my responsibility.
-你怎么打破了  -她被一顆腫瘤嚇到
- How'd you break it? - She got scared by a tumor.
是腦動靜脈畸形  而且是很可怕的一個
It's an A.V.M., and it's a scary one.
完全無法手術
Totally inoperable.
估計只能活幾個月了
Guy probably has months to live,
他和他可憐的老婆
and he and is his poor wife
想好好度過在一起剩下的時光
are just trying to make the most of their time together.
膠水怎么樣
What about glue?
什么膠水
不好意思  用在腦動靜脈畸形上
I'm sorry. For your A.V.M.--
你的腦動靜脈畸形
this A.V.M.
你看  謝博德醫生一直在說用在神經
Look, Dr. Shepherd was talking about the embolization glue
腦動靜脈畸形上的栓塞膠  然后我就想
they use in neuro A.V.M.s, and I wondered--
這種方法有沒有用在心臟上
has this approach ever been used in the heart?
我沒聽說過  所以不行
Not that I'm aware of. So... no.
在神經腦動靜脈畸形上用栓塞膠
They glue neuro A.V.M.s
因為腦血管很細微
because they’re microscopic.
這些血管太大了
These vessels are huge.
-你是說膠沒用嗎  -我是說
- You saying it won't work? - I'm saying...
我需要很多膠
I'd need a crapload of glue.
膠不起作用
I'm saying the glue won't work,
化療也不起作用
the radiation won't work,
我不想進行手術
and I don't want to go in surgically.
風險太大  會致命
I risk killing him.
所以他用腦子里的傳感器來威脅你嗎
So he's holding your sensors hostage in his skull?
這不好笑  凱麗  你得和他談談
This is not funny, Callie. You have to talk to him.
他是米基  給他一點時間
It's Mickey. Just give him a few hours.
他自己能想明白的
He'll come around.
你不想和他談
You don't want to talk to him
因為你不想看著他
because you don't want to look him in the eye
然后告訴他  你放棄了
and tell him you're bailing on this.
顯然你也不想告訴他
And you certainly don't want to tell him
你為什么放棄
why you're bailing.
為什么
Why is that?
你為亞利桑那開啟這個項目
You started this project for Arizona.
你對她沒有興趣后  對這個項目也沒興趣
When you lost interest in her, you lost interest in this.
你讓你的私人問題
You're letting your personal problems
阻礙了幾個月的研究
get in the way of months of research.
你不是也在做一樣的事情嗎
Well, you're doing the same thing.
你說過你要放棄這個研究
You said you were done with the study
多花時間陪孩子
to spend time with your kids.
這完全不同
That's completely different.
為什么不同呢  德里克
Oh, why is it different, Derek?
因為你的家庭美滿
'Cause your family's perfect,
而我的卻支離破碎嗎
and mine's a disaster?
因為你放棄這個項目去支持你老婆
Because you're leaving the study to support your wife,
而我放棄是為了忘記我的老婆嗎
and I'm doing it to forget mine?
我懂你經受了什么
I know what you're going through.
你什么都不懂
You don't know anything about it.
你們找到了解決的辦法
You guys have figured it out how to make the pieces fit.
而我本以為我也做到了  但
And I thought we did, too, but...
我只能靠自己撐過去  所以
I'm figuring this out for myself now, so...
對我寬容點  好嗎
Just bear with me, okay?
我會和米基談的
I will talk to Mickey.
我將問你一系列的問題
And I'm gonna ask you a series of questions.
你打網球嗎
"Are you a tennis player?"
神啊
Oh, good lord.
你經常用受傷的手臂
"Do you frequently carry heavy loads,
搬重的物品嗎  比如日常用品
groceries, etcetera, with your injured arm?"
我在這張床上躺了一個月了
I've been in this bed a month.
我只是想詳盡一些
I'm just trying to be thorough.
你最近進行了強烈的性交
"Have you recently engaged in any strenuous sexual--"
這個我就跳過了
I am skipping that one...
這個也跳過
Uh, too, uh...
機器顯示的不是很正常
Uh... I'm not getting a very good reading on,
先生  你
Uh, sir, are you-- oh--oh...
不關網球的事  也不關我心臟的事
It is not my tennis game, and it's not my heart.
看仔細點
Look deeper.
滾出去  把那機器也帶走
Now get out, and take that thing with you.
我擦  沒時間搞這個
Oh, come on. I don't have time for this.
胸部創傷缺血再灌注損傷
"Ischemia reperfusion injury in thoracic trauma"?
門靜脈怎么了
What happened to portal veins?
我知道局部缺血很無聊
I know ischemia is boring,
但我媽的門靜脈研究過時了
but my mother's portal vein research is outdated.
我們已經從干細胞里培植出來了
I mean, we've already grafted them from stem cells.
而且我也不想一輩子
And I don't want to spend my life
都拿來和我媽作比較
being compared to my mother.
她是位聰明的女人
She was a smart woman.
一輩子都沒拿來和她比可能更差
It might be worse to never be compared to her.
我找不到進一步研究的方法了
I can't find a way to take the research further.
這個文件也打不出來
And I can't print this damn thing!
你還好嗎
You all right?
我們用3D打印機
We've bio-engineered blood vessels
做了血管
from a 3-d printer.
對啊
Yeah.
但我不認為有人做出過門靜脈
But I don't think anyone has ever printed a portal vein.
從沒有人做過
It's never been done before.
這個膠是為大腦設計的
The glue is designed for use in your brain,
但我想在你的心臟上試一試
but I would like to try it in your heart.
這是一個大膽的方法
It--it's a bold approach.
等等  你是說
Wai--are you-- are you saying that--
我有信心可以治好你
I am optimistic that it could save your life.
完了
That's awful.
什么
I'm sorry?
在得知本的診斷結果后  你知道的
After got Ben's diagnosis, well, I mean, you--you know,
我們賣了所有東西
we--we--we sold everything.
花光了所有積蓄
We--we cashed out all our accounts.
我們刷爆了一張又一張信用卡
We maxed out our credit cards and more credit cards.
我們去了歐洲  去了印度
We went to Europe. We went to India.
還去了摩洛哥
We went to Morocco.
我們租了一整座島
We rented a whole island.
我們坐飛機去體驗失重
We--we went up in that plane where you get to be weightless.
一人五千美元
That's 5 grand a pop.
我們去了十一次  然后買了一艘船
We went up 11 times-- and then bought a boat.
再然后我們把它點了
And then we blew it up,
因為我們想看燒船的情景
'cause we wanted to watch it burn.
我們欠了一屁股的債
We owe creditors hundreds of thousands of dollars.
-你們打算怎么還這些錢  -人生保險
- How were you planning to pay for-- - Life insurance.
-本計劃的天衣無縫  -我以為是的
- Ben's a very good planner. - I thought I was.
但沒想到會活下去
I didn't plan for surviving.
但不管怎樣  親愛的
But still, hon...
我們還是得試一試  對嗎
We... we gotta try it, right?
等等
Wait.
風險有多大
What are the risks?
如我所說
Well, as I said,
從沒在心臟上做過這個手術
this has never been done before on a beating heart.
我可能會死嗎
Could I die?
我可能死在手術臺上嗎
Could I die on the table?
有可能
It's possible.
那還有希望
Then there's hope.
在手術室給我準備一個C型臂
I want a c-arm set up in the O.R.
-我可能會做胸骨切開術  -真的嗎
- I may have to do a crash sternotomy. - Really?
但我不知道會發生什么
Well, I don't know what's gonna happen.
以前又沒做過
This has never been done before.
你覺得我們需要多少動靜脈畸形膠
How much A.V.M. glue do you think we'll need?
剛說了  從沒做過這種
Again, never been done before.
隨時都可能出問題
Err's on the side of all of it.
-在哪  -什么東西在哪
- Where is it? - Where is what?
-我媽的日記  -我怎么會知道
- My mother's journal. - Why would I know?
那本黑色的書
The black book--
我今天給你的那個黑色的小本
The little black book I gave you today--
你得還給我  肖恩
I need it back, Shane.
好像給愛德華茲了
I think I left it with Edwards.
-愛德華茲  -干嗎
- Edwards! - What?
急診需要這張床  能幫我推一下嗎
E.R. needs this bed. Can you help me?
博斯克先生是怎么了
Hey, and what is going on with Mr. Bosco?
腳扭了為什么要被挪去
Why has a broken ankle been moved to pre-op
-做心臟手術的術前準備  -什么
- for a cardiac procedure? - What?
你不能就這樣改變療程  還沒有
You can't change the course of treatment like that without...
不是我  心臟科診治宣稱無法手術
I didn't. The cardio consult declared it inoperable.
那他怎么還做術前準備  誰
So then why is he in pre-op? Who--
-誰做的會診  -是楊醫生
- Who did the consult? - Dr. Yang!
-怎么了  -抱歉  我們剛才在這里
- What? - Sorry. We were in here before,
我好像把手機落在這了
and I think I left my... phone.
這是準備做什么手術
Well, what do we have here?
心室動靜脈畸形啊
Oh, a ventricular A.V.M.
我要用膠做液體栓塞
I'm doing liquid embolization with glue.
等等  是用來治腦動脈瘤的膠嗎
Wait, glue for brain aneurysms?
這種手術有人做過么
Has that been tried on a heart before?
謝謝  事實上
Thank you. As a matter of fact,
還真沒有
no.
確定能治好么
Are you sure it'll work?
也不確定
That is also a no.
你真是太勇氣可嘉了哦
I-I am impressed with your enormous balls.
我還真想在這觀看
I wish I could stick around and watch this.
我是克里斯蒂娜
I'm Cristina... by the way.
克里斯蒂娜·楊  知道了吧
Cristina Yang. Just so you know.
我知道  我們見過幾次面
Yeah, I know. We've met a couple of times, actually.
我是艾瑪·瑪琳
Emma Marling.
我知道  我意思是  我是歐文的
I know. I'm--I'm saying I'm Owen's, um...
前妻
Ex-wife.
對
Yes.
沒錯
Right.
這真是太棒了
Well, this looks amazing.
我迫不及待想知道結果了
And I can't wait to hear how it went.
晚安
Good night.
你都不和我道別么
You weren't gonna say good night?
這個啊  我下班了  一會兒見
Oh, hey. I'm off. I'll-- I'll see you later.
會見嗎
Will you?
可能不會  我大概會很晚回去
Probably not. I'll probably be late.
你在跟別人約會嗎
Are you seeing someone else?
是不是這樣
Is that what's happening?
我就是想知道
'Cause I just need to know.
-不是這樣  -那是怎么回事
- Oh, it's not that. - Then what is it?
跟你沒關系
It's none of your business.
這是我和謝博德之間的事
It is between me and Shepherd,
他該知道的我都說了
and I told him everything he needs to know.
米基
Mickey...
米基  看著我
Mickey, look at me.
如果我看你  外星人就會贏的
If I do, the aliens will win.
這手術會讓你喪命
This operation could kill you.
我沒跟你說過我是怎么變成廢物的吧
I never told you how I became a quad, did I?
你發生了車禍
You were in a car accident.
是我制造了一場車禍
I caused a car accident...
因為我喝醉了  我喝多了
Because I was drunk. I got drunk,
還開車  我撞上了另一輛車
and I drove, and I hit another car,
撞死了兩個十幾歲的女孩
and I killed two teenage girls--
琳賽和謝麗爾
Lindsay and Cheryl.
我只能這么待著  廢物一個
So there I am, a pile of garbage.
既不能動又不能離開  什么都干不了
Can't move, can't walk, can't do anything
只能回想我對那些家庭
except think about what I did...
犯的錯
to those families.
而現在竟然還有人照顧我
I've got people tending to me.
有人喂我吃飯
People feed me,
給我刮胡須  給我洗澡
and shave me and clean me,
我不值得他們為我花時間
and I don't deserve their time.
我就該死在那輛車里
I deserve... to have died in that car.
我每天都這么想
And I wish I did every day...
已經九年了
for nine years.
當你讓我
And when you asked me...
加入這個項目時
to do this...
當我有機會
When I had a chance to do something
做些對別人有利的事情時
affecting someone in a good way...
第一次
For the first time,
我覺得自己有了價值
I thought I was worth having around.
如果我死了
If I die,
把我的大腦捐去研究  我還能有用
give my brain to science, and I still help.
讓我幫助你們
Let me help.
求你了
Please.
需要什么嗎
And how can I help you?
是你啊  和昨晚一樣的嗎
Oh, hey. Same as last night?
是的  謝謝
Yeah, thanks.
你是真的喜歡這些人吧
You must really like these guys, huh?
我還是覺得這主意不咋地
I still think it's a bad idea.
我知道  但這是對的
I-I know, but it's the right idea.
米基沒什么損失  反而會有所獲
Mickey has nothing to lose and a lot to gain.
好吧  把他排在明早
Okay, I'll schedule him for tomorrow morning.
不  等等  我明早不能做
Oh, no, wait. I can't do tomorrow morning.
貝利要做產后優生測試
Bailey has a well-baby exam,
我要連做兩個脊椎間板脫位癥手術
I've got back-to-back discotomies,
還有  我得帶佐拉去報舞蹈課
and Zola and I were gonna check out a dance class.
只能今晚做了
It's gonna have to be tonight.
佐拉  你和弟弟要回日托所
Zola, you and your brother are gonna have to go back to day care
再待一會兒了  好嗎  親愛的
for a little while longer, okay, sweetie?
不用你去了  我來送
No, no, no. I'll take 'em back up. I got it.
這邊  來吧  寶貝
Here. Come on. This way, babes.
呼羅斯醫生
Page Dr. Ross.
好的
Okay.
再加點膠
More glue.
我們的膠快用完了
We're getting to the end of our supply.
那就再去拿點
Then go get more.
我需要補上這整塊
I think I need to fill this whole thing.
導管卡在靜脈里了
Okay... the catheter is stuck to the vein.
天吶  這玩意真緊
God, this stuff is intense.
這么使勁拽好嗎
Should you be tugging that hard?
你想讓我把它留在里面嗎
Well, you want me to leave it in there?
好了  搞定了
Okay. Okay, we're good.
你是怎么想到的
How did you come up with this?
不知道  就是簡單的聯想
I don't know. I just... connected the dots.
你真是驚奇無限啊  小鯊魚
You are full of surprises, sharky.
奇思妙想  又斗勁十足
Innovative instincts and killer instincts--
還有什么絕活
What other secrets are hiding in there?
你覺得還有什么
What do you think you'll find?
如果不是關節炎  滑囊炎或肌腱套炎
Well, if it's not arthritis or bursitis or rotator cuff,
而且你心臟也沒事  那就不該痛
and your heart's fine, then it can't hurt.
除非是牽涉痛導致的神經反跳
Unless it's referred pain, which could be nerve impingement
或是橫隔膜受刺激  這樣的話
or diaphragmatic irritation, so...
你根本就不用照X光
You don't need an x-ray.
棒極了
Bravo.
你需要做超聲檢查
You need an ultrasound.
希望你不是認為我懷孕了
Well, I hope you're not thinking I'm pregnant!
叫愛德華茲醫生到這  馬上
Page Dr. Edwards here stat. Right away.
我需要做超聲檢查
I need an ultrasound.
你懷孕了  阿歷克斯知道嗎
Are you pregnant? Does Alex know?
不是  我只是需要一臺超聲儀
No, I-I need an ultrasound machine.
你見到愛德華茲嗎
Have you seen Edwards?
阿歷克斯以為我懷孕了么
Does Alex think I'm pregnant?
我有個和這一樣的馬克杯
I have a mug like that.
你去哪了
Where the hell have you been?
我以為你走了
Uh, I thought you were leaving,
而且我和楊醫生發現了一個
and Dr. Yang and I found
左腦室動靜脈畸形的病人
a left ventricle A.V.M.
那你現在在這了  進來手術吧
Yeah, well, you're here now. Scrub in.
我拒絕
I'd rather not.
肖恩  你得忘掉它
Shane, you gotta get past this.
讓你參與手術可不是為了安慰你
You're not a consolation prize.
而是你有真材實料
You deserve to be here.
布魯克斯的天賦...
Brooks had a gift that needed to be...
我不想和你共事
I don't wanna work with you.
我對這科沒興趣
I'm not interested.
我說得夠清楚了吧
Can I be more clear?
挺清楚了
I suppose not.
你走吧
Go.
時間才能見證療效
To a certain extent, time will tell.
現在我們確定的是你的心臟沒有受到損害
What we know for sure is we've done no damage to your heart,
而且在這種初期階段
and at this preliminary stage,
腦動靜脈畸形不會繼續發展
it appears the A.V.M. won't continue to grow.
那就是說
So you're saying...
我會活下去
I'll live?
是的
Yes.
我的天吶
Dear god.
-本  親愛的  -我懂
- Ben? Honey? - I know.
不會有事的
We'll be all right.
我知道花了太多錢  這一年太瘋狂了
I know it's a lot of money. It's been a crazy year,
但我的世界不能沒有你
but the world is a lot more fun with you in it.
只要我們倆在一起  一切都會沒事的
As long as we have each other, everything will be fine.
-喬伊斯  我們玩完了  -是的
- Joyce, we're screwed. - I know.
我們不只是破產  我們還是罪犯
We're not just bankrupt. We're criminals.
我們很可能會坐牢
I think we might go to jail.
我們簡直親手埋葬了自己
Oh, we're so incredibly screwed.
就像廉價妓女作踐自己一樣
Like a $2 whore.
楊  那是我的踝關節骨折病人
Yang, that's my broken ankle.
下次在偷我的病人之前
How about a little heads-up
知會我一聲好么
next time you wanna steal one of my patients?
他們怎么了
What happened to them?
我救了他
I saved his life.
我知道你救了他
So I get that you saved him,
但他是我的病人  你得提前跟我說
but he was my patient, and you should've told me before you...
我想出了治療方案  而你沒有
I came up with the fix. You didn't.
如果你還因那晚的事而生氣
If you're still pissed about what happened the other night.
我   我在和杰克森交往
I... I'm with Jackson.
上次那事的確不該發生  也不會有下次
It was inappropriate, and it's not gonna happen again.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
你親了我  肖恩
When you kissed me, Shane.
是那個啊
Oh. That.
我們那時很激動  所以就發生了
We were excited. It happened.
我很抱歉你想多了
I'm sorry it meant more to you--
-沒想多  -那你還說
- It didn't. - You're still talking about it.
你怎么回事啊
What's happened to you?
你倆在嘀咕啥
What are you guys whispering about?
-沒事  -天吶  你們  好吧
- Nothing. - God, you guys, fine.
是亞利桑那·羅賓斯
It's Arizona Robbins.
但別到處說好嗎
But please don't say anything, okay?
-因為她不想  -羅賓斯
- Because she really doesn't need...  - Robbins?
就是說  你現在是拉拉了
So... you're gay now?
肖恩  成熟點  這東西沒定性的
Shane, grow up. It's a sliding scale.
我只是對她有點好感而已
I slide over her way.
如果你見人就貼標簽
If you really have to label everything,
那就給我貼"熱戀中"
then label me "in love."
墨菲
Murphy!
很抱歉  他們猜得七七八八了
I'm sorry. They pretty much figured it out.
不  我才要道歉  因為我得跟你說實話了
No. I'm sorry, because I'm about to be very frank.
那晚我做了非常糟糕的決定
The other night was a bad call on my part.
我那時很孤獨  而且當時很愉悅
I was lonely, and it was... lovely.
但僅僅只是那一晚
But it was-- it was one night,
不會再有下一次
and that's all that it will ever be,
所以如果這和你預期不一樣
so if you had different expectations,
那就慢慢適應
please adjust them.
當然
Of course.
你不需要道歉  這是我的錯
There's no need to apologize. It's my fault.
我從不和別人深交
I don't open up to people much,
而只要和別人交往深入點
and when I try to open up a little bit,
我就會得意忘形  以前就有過
I can get carried away. It's happened before.
而你
And you...
我一直很欣賞作為外科醫生的你
I've just always admired you as... a surgeon,
還有你這個人
and--and a person,
所以我以為你有那個意思
and the thought that you thought about me...
我卻誤解了
I misunderstood.
我想過頭了  很抱歉
Um, I went overboard, and I'm sorry.
不會有下次
It won't happen again.
莉亞
Leah...
謝謝你的理解
Thank you for understanding.
杜松子酒  加冰
Gin, rocks.
你不會要我買單吧
You gonna charge me again?
別的酒吧對樂隊都免費啦
Most places comp the bands, you know?
這杯我請
I got this one.
謝謝
Appreciate that.
吉米·埃文斯
Jimmy Evans.
你好
Hey.
我認識你
I know you.
我這幾天一直有來
I've, uh, been here the last couple of nights.
不  我不是說這個
No. Something else.
天吶
Oh, my god.
你是醫院里的
You're a doctor...
醫生
at the hospital.
被你發現了
Guilty.
你每晚都來這干嘛
What brings you back here every night?
聽你彈奏  我喜歡你的歌
Oh, uh, you. I mean, I like your set.
其實我是喜歡艾伯特·柯林斯的歌
Uh, I like the Albert Collins stuff.
美國布魯斯吉他大師
耳力不錯嘛  你會彈嗎
Ah. You got a good ear, then. You play?
小時候我爸教過我一點
My dad taught me a little when I was a kid,
但他后來沒繼續教我了
but, uh, he didn't stick with it.
那你應該堅持去自學
Aw, you should have stuck with it.
彈吉他能給你帶來很多東西
Look where it could've taken you.
雖說不能當醫生救死扶傷
I mean, instead of saving people's lives,
但你可以來這給四個聽眾
you could be playing 70-year-old songs
演奏首懷舊老歌
to four people in a giant ashtray.
你是哪方面的醫生
What kind of doctor are you?
小兒科醫生
Pediatric surgeon.
嬰兒  小孩
Babies, kids.
我這輩子見過兒科醫生一次
I met a pediatric surgeon once.
我人生中最恐怖的一晚
Scariest night of my life.
我兒子兩歲都不到
My son's not even 2 years old.
我給他吃草莓  他噎著了
I'm feeding him strawberries, and he starts choking.
臉色發紫
Turned blue.
趕緊送他去醫院  醫生把他救活了
We take him in, they get him breathing again.
兒科醫生給他插管
Pediatric surgeon runs the tube down his throat,
把噎著他的東西取出
and got the thing out.
救了我兒子  也救了我
Saved my boy's life. Saved my life, too.
如果那晚我兒子死了
If I'd lost my little boy that night,
我估計也活不下去了
I never would've made it. I never would've survived.
幸好沒事啊
I'm glad it worked out for you.
是啊  真心得感謝你們兒科醫生啊
Yeah. Thank god for you guys, man. Seriously.
你兒子在哪
So where is he?
你家人呢
Now, I mean. Where's your family?
這個問題很復雜
That's a complicated answer.
這酒吧都沒什么人了
This place has really cleared out.
看來我真有"魅力"啊
I guess I was the big draw.
是的啊
Yeah, well...
我也該走了
I probably should head out myself.
你會彈吉他嗎
I was gonna say, you play a little?
我多出一把吉他
I got an extra guitar.
我們可以一起彈啊
We can get up and make some noise.
不了  我就小時候彈過  之后就沒彈了
No. No, I haven't played since I was a kid.
反正沒人聽  彈不好也沒關系
Well, there's no one here to hear you suck.
一起啊  很好玩的
Come on. It'll be fun.
我什么曲子都不懂
I don't know any songs.
還記得你爸爸教你彈的曲子嗎
What about the songs your daddy taught you?
我可能會彈
I might know one of those.
是不是心律有變化
Am I hearing changes in his rhythm?
請打開心臟檢測儀
Turn up the heart monitor, please.
開了
Done.
增加甘露醇劑量
More mannitol.
心律混亂  血壓上升
Rhythm's getting very erratic, and--and B.P.'s rising.
安靜
Quiet. Quiet.
好  先停下手術
All right. Reverse the paralytics.
檢查嘔吐反射
All right, let me check his gag reflexes.
不要啊  米基  加把勁
Oh, no, Mickey. Come on. No.
謝博德醫生  沒有任何腦活動
Dr. Shepherd, there's no brain activity.
那是
That is a...
胰腺假性囊腫  萬歲
pancreatic pseudocyst! Bam!
你剛才高呼”萬歲”了
Did you just say "bam"?
這是牽涉性疼痛吧
It had to be referred pain, right?
但肩部牽涉性疼痛
But referred pain to the shoulder
是隔膜刺激的癥狀
means irritation of the diaphragm,
這看似不合理  但是
which did not make sense, but...
你有胰液外漏
you have pancreatic fluid leakage,
所以我在想
so I was thinking, well, maybe something
也許是有什么刺激到隔膜
was aggravating the diaphragm,
導致肩部牽涉性疼痛
which referred to the shoulder,
然后  萬歲
And bam!
胰腺假性囊腫
Pancreatic pseudocyst.
也許在告知病人的時候
Maybe you should wipe that smile off your face
不要笑得這么開心
before you tell the patient.
天啊  抱歉
Oh, god. I am so sorry.
我忘記這不是個好消息
I-I forgot that this is bad news.
那你為什么笑啊
And... you're laughing.
這是我首次覺得  你讓我放心了
For the first time today, I feel like I'm in good hands.
干得好  威爾遜
Nice work, Wilson.
你找到病源了
You traced it back to the source.
我準備接手我媽媽的研究
Hey! I'm doing my mother's research,
但不是你說的那個原因哦
but not for the reasons you said I should.
-別鬧  格蕾  -是因為她的想法很好
- Not now, Grey. - She had a good idea!
我不是沾她的光  我是延續她的熱情
I'm not riding her coattails. I am sharing her passion.
或許這就是我母親留給我的
Maybe this is what my mother gave me.
你爸把你教的不錯啊
Your daddy taught you pretty good.
向前走*
*Go ahead
親愛的孩子*
*Pretty baby
向前走  享受人生*
*Go ahead, knock yourself out
我一直愛著你  寶貝*
*I still love you, baby
你是如此純潔無暇*
*'Cause you don't know what it's all about
明亮燈光*
*Bright lights
大都市*
*Big city
都讓孩子眼花繚亂*
*Gone to my baby's head
明亮燈光*
*Bright lights
大都市*
*Big city
沒事吧
You okay?
這首歌真不錯
You know... that's a good tune.
讓我想起很多以前的事
Brings back a lot.
如果你不提醒自己
You know, if you're not careful,
以前犯下的錯誤就會很困擾你
all your old mistakes can just roll up on you.
我也教我的孩子彈吉他
I taught my kid to play guitar, too.
就像你說的
It's like you said.
我多希望我當時堅持下去
I wish I'd had stuck with it.
也許你孩子堅持彈吉他了
Well, your kid probably does, too.
但時光無法倒流  是吧
Yeah, but there's no going back, is there?
你想看看他的照片嗎
Can I show you a picture of him?
我兒子
My boy?
你有他的照片啊
What, you have one?
這是尼基
That's Nicky.
他那時五歲  現在差不多十二歲了
He's 5 there. He'd be about 12 now.
旁邊那位是他媽媽娜奧米
And, uh, that's his mom, Naomi.
她是日本人
She's Japanese.
這是
Who's...
他們現在在哪
Where are they?
南佛羅里達州
South Florida.
我很久沒有回去了
I haven't been back there in years.
天啊  你真是死性不改啊
God, you just keep doing this.
什么意思
What do you mean?
放過這個孩子  永遠都別回去
Do this kid a favor. Don't ever go back.
讓他好好長大
Let him grow up
不要讓他知道你是個爛人
without knowing you any more that he already has.
搞什么啊
What the hell, man?
這樣對他比較好  你知道的
He's better off. You know that.
你怎么了啊
What's your problem?
剛才還好好的
We were having fun here.
我是在保護你兒子  你兒子沒你更好
I'm trying to protect your kid. You're no good to him.
你不了解我  也輪不到你來說我兒子
Hey, you don't know me, and you don't talk about my kid.
別動手
Hey! no!
滾
Out!
給我滾
You, out, now!
這樣對大家再好不過了
This way, you can do the most good for the most people.
你真這樣認為
You think so?
他會很欣慰的
He would be grateful.
你所做的正是他希望的
You did exactly what he wanted.
我不會退出這個項目
I'm not dropping the project.
你是對的
You were right.
我開始是為了她
I was doing it for her.
現在我要為造福他人完成它
And now I will do it for a million people
即使我見不到他們
I'll never even meet.
也是為了米基
And for Mickey.
我非常需要你的幫助
I could really use your help.
我們才剛剛有點了解
We were just starting to learn
大腦神經連接之廣袤
the extent of the brain's connections...
連接之遠  連接之深
How far they reach, how deep they go.
我已經不知道該怎么說我自己了
I think I've ceased to exist.
我今天創造了歷史  實話實說
I made history today, literally.
給無法手術的病人手術
Operated on the inoperable,
把病人從死亡中拯救出來
saved a man from certain death,
但卻毀了他的生活
and then ruined his life.
還有  歐文
Oh, also Owen
好像跟那個叫瑪琳的處得很好
seems very happy with that Marling person
而他卻從沒跟她提起過我
to whom he has never even mentioned me.
就好像過去幾年什么事都沒發生過一樣
It's as if the last few years never happened.
還有  賣紙巾的自動售貨機
Also, the automatic paper towel thingy
認不出我是個人類
won't recognize me as human.
我就站在那  像個傻子一樣揮著手
I'm just standing there, waving my hands like an idiot.
對不起  你說什么
I'm sorry. What?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
申請研究基金
Application for research funding.
你選好項目了
Oh, you picked your project.
我要做3D打印的門靜脈
I'm gonna 3-D print portal veins.
這太棒了  梅
That is amazing, Mer.
-你打算如何  -好了  別說了
- How are you gonna do that-- - Okay, don't.
所以我才沒有告訴你
It's why I didn't tell you.
我有一份事業和一個家庭
I have a career and a family,
我決定要同時照顧兩方面
and I'm going to do both.
我沒有時間聽你說我做不來什么
What I don't have time for is for you to tell me that I can't.
我從沒說過這種話
I never said that.
你知道  我一直支持你
You know, I was always there for you,
無論你想要什么
for whatever you needed.
現在要你來支持我了
And now this is when I need you,
你應該來幫我
and you're supposed to help me.
然而相反地  上周你把我推到一邊
And instead, last week you pushed me aside
就因為我有了孩子
because I had a baby.
你是現在沒時間考慮我嗎
You don't have time for me now?
是你從來就不想
Because you don't have time
為了那些和你追求不一樣的人付出
for people who want things that you don't want.
但我們知道所有的連接都很重要
But we know that every connection matters.
每一個連接都很關鍵
Every connection is crucial.
我  我還得把這做完
I-I-I have to finish this.
如果有一個斷開了
And when one is broken...
那通常說明某處已有損傷
It usually means some damage has been done.
我不知道是你有了別人
I can't figure it out if you're seeing someone else
還是你覺得我懷孕了
or you think that you knocked me up,
所以
So...
我試著回想問題究竟出在哪
I tried to trace it back to the root of the problem,
然后我認為是因為你爸爸
and I think it's your dad.
聽著  我告訴過你
Look, I told you--
別再提起這事  我知道
Not to bring it up again, I know,
但這是最后一次  因為如果我搞錯了
and this is the last time, because if I'm wrong--
你沒錯  你應該為自己感到驕傲
You're not wrong. You should be proud of yourself.
我本該不去招惹他
I could've let him just pass through,
但你卻總說什么"和他談談
but you were all "talk to him,
不然你后半輩子肯定要后悔"
you'll wonder for the rest of your life."
很好  謝謝
Well, thanks.
十八年前跟他鬧翻時  我以為
I didn't know I could feel this crappy again
我再也不會那樣生氣了
after 18 frickin' years!
這種連接的系統驅使我們行動
This system of connections compels us to act
作出選擇以及如何表現
and choose and behave...
有時似乎違背了我們的本意的
Sometimes seemingly against our own will.
短信
莉亞·墨菲
你在干什么呢
發送
但并不是無章可循的
But it is not random at all.
它是我們之所以成為我們的藍圖
It is the map of who we are.
你收到我的短信了嗎
Did you get my text?
對不起  我有事耽擱了
Sorry. I was stuck there.
我必須今晚把那做好
I had to get this thing out by tonight.
我也有點事情
I got hung up, too.
我剛剛把他們哄睡著
I just barely got them down.
-剛剛  -我知道
- Just now? - I know.
這么晚
It's so late.
我知道  我盡力了
I know. I tried.
這樣下去不行
It's not working.
對  不行
No, it isn't.
我們沒法又忙工作又忙孩子
We just can't seem to make the pieces fit.
我同意  但我不知道還能怎樣
I agree, but I don't know how--
我有辦法
I think I do.
我想多花點時間在BCI研究上
I wanna spend more time on this B.C.I. research.
B.C.I.  基于運動想象的腦機接口
托瑞斯和我  今天開了個好頭
Torres and I... blew it wide open today.
-所以你想花更多時間工作  -不
- So you wanna take on more? - No.
其實是更少
Less, actually.
今年對你來說很重要
This is a big year for you,
你得花時間搞好自己的工作
and you need time to make it work.
我已經經歷過了  我可以先退回來
I had a big year. I can step back,
少做點手術  專心做科研
scale down the surgery, focus on this research,
多花時間陪孩子
spend time with the kids,
給你更多時間
and give you the slack you need
把這一年過得充實
to make this year count.
我不喜歡
I don't like it.
-什  -你會恨我的
- Wh-- - You'll resent me,
孩子們也會恨我的
and so will the kids,
而且  我不想變成我母親那樣
and... I don't wanna be my mother.
你不是你母親  你知道的
You're not your mother. You know that.
我們會繼續努力試著理解我們自己
We will work to understand ourselves...
解開這個謎團
Solve the puzzle...
這不公平
It feels unfair.
跟孩子們在一起又不是什么稱心的獎勵
Spending time with the kids is not a consolation prize.
這就是獎勵
It is the prize.
你要公平嗎  也許以后
You want fair? Maybe down the road,
我會讓你跟他們在一起過一年
I'll give you a year with them.
也許等佐拉開始出去約會的
Maybe when Zola's dating,
因為我可不想那會兒成天在她身邊攪局
'cause I don't wanna be around for that.
我愛你
I love you.
你可是該愛我  我為你做了多大的犧牲啊
Well, you should. What I'm doing is amazing for you.
你的日子會比我的更有趣
You're gonna have more fun than me.
我知道  原來杯子在這
I know. Oh, so that's where that went.
是啊  這是我們的嗎
Yeah. Is that ours?
是的
Yes.
這些連接是如何工作的
how all the connections work
以及零碎的片段是如何
and all the pieces...
完美結合的
fit.